
/* Python Quiz Questions
 * creating an array and passing the number, questions, options, and answers 
 */

let questions = [

/* Q1 */     
	{
      numb: 1,
      question: "Who developed Python Programming Language?",
      options: [
                "A) Wick van Rossum",
                "B) Rasmus Lerdorf",
                "C) Guido van Rossum",
                "D) Niene Stom"
               ],
      answer: "C) Guido van Rossum"
    },
/*Copy till here*/


/* Q2 */     
	{
      numb: 2,
      question: "Which type of Programming does Python support?",
      options: [
                "A) object-oriented programming ",
                "B) structured programming",
                "C) functional programming",
                "D) all of the mentioned"
               ],
      answer: "D) all of the mentioned"
    },
/*Copy till here*/

/* Q3 */     
	{
      numb: 3,
      question: "Which of the following is the correct extension of the Python file?",
      options: [
                "A) .python",
                "B) .pl",
                "C) .py",
                "D).p"
               ],
      answer: "C) .py"
    },
/*Copy till here*/
	
/* Q4 */     
	{
      numb: 4,
      question: "Is Python code compiled or interpreted?",
      options: [
                "A) Python code is both compiled and interpreted",
                "B) Python code is neither compiled nor interpreted",
                "C) Python code is only compiled",
                "D) Python code is only interpreted"
               ],
      answer: "B) Python code is neither compiled nor interpreted"
    },
/*Copy till here*/
	
/* Q5 */     
	{
      numb: 5,
      question: "All keywords in Python are in _________",
      options: [
                "A) Capitalized",
                "B) ower case",
                "C) UPPER CASE",
                "D) None of the mentioned"
               ],
      answer: "D) None of the mentioned"
    },
/*Copy till here*/

/* Q6 */     
	{
      numb: 6,
      question: "Which keyword is used for function in Python language?",
      options: [
                "A) Function",
                "B) Def",
                "C) Fun",
                "D) Define"
               ],
      answer: "B) Def"
    },
/*Copy till here*/

/* Q7 */     
	{
      numb: 7,
      question: "Which of the following functions can help us to find the version of python that we are currently working on?",
      options: [
                "A) sys.version(1)",
                "B) sys.version(0)",
                "C) sys.version()",
                "D) sys.version"
               ],
      answer: "A) sys.version(1)"
    },
/*Copy till here*/

/* Q8 */ 
	{
      numb: 8,
      question: "Python supports the creation of anonymous functions at runtime, using a construct called __________",
      options: [
                "A) pi",
                "B) anonymous",
                "C) lambda",
                "D) none of the mentioned"
               ],
      answer: "C) lambda"
    },
/*Copy till here*/

/* Q9 */ 
	{
      numb: 9,
      question: "What does pip stand for python?",
      options: [
                "A) unlimited length",
                "B) all private members must have leading and trailing underscores",
                "C) Preferred Installer Program",
                "D)  none of the mentioned"
               ],
      answer: "C) Preferred Installer Program"
    },
/*Copy till here*/


/* Q10 */    
	{
      numb: 10,
      question: "Which of the following functions is a built-in function in python?",
      options: [
                "A) factorial()",
                "B) print()",
                "C) seed()",
                "D) sqrt()"
               ],
      answer: "B) print()"
    },
/*Copy till here*/


]; /* Array close*/